chikka.com 2018-03-16

# Privacy Policy - Chikka

To provide you with the best customer experience, Voyager Innovations, Inc. is committed to protecting your privacy and staying transparent with the way we handle your personal information. For this we have designed a privacy policy that will help you understand how we collect, use, store, share and protect the personal information you have entrusted us. 

Our privacy policy values and protects your personal information under the Data Privacy Act of 2012 and the laws of the Philippines. Personal information simply means any information or data that can be used to distinguish, identify or contact you. 

Our Privacy Policy explains: 

1\. Why we collect personal information 

2\. What kind information we collect 

3\. Where we get these information 

4\. Who we share your information with 

5\. How we protect your information

6\. Your choices, including how you can check and update any personal information we have about you 

7\. What happens if there are changes in our privacy policy 

As a condition for use of our products and services, you are consenting to the Privacy Policy of Voyager Innovations, Inc. (we, our, us) and its subsidiaries, affiliates, and subcontractors; and the collection, use, access, transfer, storage and processing of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

To improve our products and services, it is important that we collect, use, process and analyze your personal information when it is reasonable and necessary. When we can, we aggregate and anonymize this information such that you are never identified as an individual. [Aggregating simply means presenting information in segments or categories like age groups; anonymizing means removing personally identifiable information from the data]. 

In particular, we are using your information to:

1\. Manage your account, provide customer care activities, monitor the quality and security of the network, train our staff, and provide services timely and efficiently; 

2\. Send commercial and promotional advertisements, loyalty and rewards offers, surveys, customer care and aftersales communications, and other broadcast push messages; 

3\. Send commercial and promotional advertisements, loyalty and rewards offers, surveys, customer care and aftersales communications, and other broadcast push messages; 

4\. Conduct analysis for research and marketing initiatives, including the generation of anonymized or non-personally identifiable location and mobility data to show footfall, location patterns, crowd density, and other information that may be relevant for marketing purposes; 

5\. Generate statistical insights based on usage/network information to assist the Government in planning for healthcare, disaster, and other similar initiatives; 

6\. Run credit scoring programs and initiatives, including but not limited to, providing information to the Credit Information Corporation in accordance to Republic Act No. 9501, otherwise known as the Credit Information System Act; and 

7\. Perform such other processing or disclosure that may be required under law or regulations. 

In cases where your separate and full consent is given, we are also processing your personal data to:

1\. Create your personal profile based on your interests, preferences, mobility patterns from physical locations that you may visit, and other information that may be relevant for marketing and market research purposes;

2\. Share your personal profile based on your interests, preferences, and mobility patterns from physical locations that you may visit, to our business partners and third-party service providers; 

3\. Compute your credit score based on data collected internally within the PLDT Group and its subsidiaries and affiliates, and share your credit score to third-parties to whom you specifically instruct us to share your credit score; and 

4\. Send you information on offers, promotions, and advertisements from our business partners and third-party service providers.

We collect information to provide better services to all of our users. This may range from the most basic like being able to offer promos that best suites the user’s to more complex use cases like which related services and digital content a user might find interesting & useful. This includes information such as: 

  * Basic personal information like your name, date of birth, gender, nationality, address, and identity supporting documents such as social security, passport, or tax identification numbers. You can check what we know about you by making a request to the Voyager Data Privacy Compliance Officer through the contact details provided below; 
  * Your credit card, bank and payment details; and 
  * Your contact details like billing address, telephone number, mobile phone number, email address; 

There are a few different ways we collect information.

##  Information that you personally give us 

Most of the personal information we have are those that you have given us yourself. You provide us personal information when you:

  * Sign up to use our products and services by creating an account in our web sites or applications; 
  * Apply for subscription to our services by filling out a Service Application Form or Customer Information Sheet or provide personal information to one of our TeleSales representative; 
  * Get in touch with us to ask about something, file a complaint or request for service; 
  * Take part in our research and surveys; 
  * Sign up in our booth in trade shows or events; and/or 
  * When you apply for job with us. 

##  Information we collect during our relationship with you 

We also collect information as you use our products & services, like when you:

  * Use our networks - whether it is mobile, Wi-Fi, or other channels; 
  * Pay your bill or purchase add-on products and services; 
  * Use our apps, websites and self-service channels; 
  * Purchase items from our apps and websites; and 
  * Join our promos, prize raffles or reward & loyalty programs 

We also collect anonymous information to help us tailor our Web sites and Applications to visitor interests and concerns; we also use this to improve our Applications for overall user experience. We use "cookies" to help us understand which parts of our Web sites and Applications are the most popular, where our users are going and how much time they spend there. The information that is gathered through cookies is used solely to assist in improving both our Web sites and Applications design and function. Our Web sites are functional without the retention of cookies. You may elect to block cookies from our Web sites through your browser settings. 

We also automatically track certain information about you based upon your behavior on our Web site and Applications. We use this information to do internal research on our Users’ demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand, protect and serve you and our community. This information may include browsing history and your IP address. 

##  Information we collect from other sources 

We also collect information from commercially or publicly available sources like published directories and public documents. We may also obtain your personal information from third parties (credit agencies) and from other sources which you have given consent for the disclosure of such information relating to you and where otherwise lawfully permitted. 

We will never share, rent or sell your personal information to third parties outside Voyager Innovations, Inc. (or the group of companies of which Voyager Innovations, Inc. is part of) except in limited circumstances as noted in this policy. In some instances, we may be required to disclose your personal information to our agents, subsidiaries, affiliates, partners and other third party agencies as part of business operations and the provision of our products and services. This means we might share your information with: 

  * Our partner companies, organizations, or agencies including their sub-contractors or prospective business partners that act as our service providers, contractors, professional advisers who help us provide our products and services, for example our couriers for bill delivery and our customer contact centers for our hotline operations; 
  * Other companies in the PLDT Group of companies; 
  * Law enforcement and government agencies; and 
  * Other companies whom you have also given consent to share your information 

The integrity, confidentiality and security of your information are particularly important to us. That’s why we strictly enforce our privacy policy within the company and we have implemented technological, organizational and physical security measures that are designed to protect your information from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure. We also put in effect safeguards such as: 

1\. We keep and protect your information using a secured server behind a firewall, encryption and security controls; 

2\. We restrict access to your information only to qualified and authorized personnel who hold your information with strict confidentiality; 

3\. We undergo regular audit and rigorous testing of our infrastructure’s security protocols to ensure your data is always protected; and 

4\. We let you update your information securely to keep our records accurate 

We will retain your personal data throughout the subscription of our products and services, and for a maximum period of five (5) years afterward. 

You are afforded certain rights in relation to your personal data under the Data Privacy Act of 2012, which includes the right to object to processing, the right to access your data, the right to modify of inaccurate data, and the right to erasure or blocking of data. 

If you wish to have access to your personal information in our records; or you think that such personal information we have of you is incomplete, not up-to-date, or otherwise inaccurate, you may get in touch with our Data Privacy Officer through the contact details provided below. 

Our Contact Details: 

Data Privacy Compliance Officer

dpo@voyagerinnovation.com

From time to time, Voyager Innovations, Inc. may change this privacy policy to comply with government and regulatory requirements; to adapt to new technologies and protocols; to align with industry practices; or for other legitimate purposes. You will always be provided notice if these changes are material and, if we are required by law, we will also obtain your consent. 

## Subsidiaries and Affiliates

  * Smart Communications, Inc. 
  * PLDT 
  * ePLDT
  * Digitel Mobile Philippines, Inc. (Sun Cellular)
  * Cignal TV
  * PayMaya Philippines, Inc. (formerly Smart eMoney, Inc.)
  * FINTQnologies Corp.
  * FINTQ Inventures Insurance Agency Corp. (Surelite Insurance Agency) 
  * Takatack Technologies Pte. Ltd.
  * Takatack Holdings Pte. Ltd.

## Partners

  * 2GO Express Inc.
  * aCommerce
  * Adyen
  * AFDigital Inc.
  * Airspeed International Corporation
  * Alibaba Group Holding Limited (AnyProxy)
  * Amazon Web Services, Inc.
  * Apple Inc.
  * Asiapay Payment Technology Corp.
  * Atlassian, Inc. (JIRA)
  * Autodesk, Inc.
  * BDO Unibank, Inc.
  * Braintree
  * CC Mobile Financial Services Philippines (Cash Credit)
  * Cliqnship Corp.
  * Curo Teknika Inc.
  * Degreed, Inc.
  * Dragonpay Corporation
  * DSTNCT Pte. Ltd.
  * Ematic Solutions PTE. LTD. 
  * Facebook, Inc.
  * FindShare
  * Globe Telecom, Inc.
  * Google
  * Gotuaco, del Rosario Insurance Brokers, Inc.
  * Graymatics, Inc.
  * Hashtag Digital, Inc.
  * HubSpot, Inc.
  * i4asia Corporation (FreshDesk)
  * IdeasXmachina Advertising, Inc. (IXM)
  * iPay88 Sdn Bhd
  * Jam2Go Express Corp.
  * LBC Express, Inc.
  * LBP Service Corporation
  * Media 5 Marketing Corporation
  * Microsoft Corporation
  * MOLPay Sdn Bhd.
  * Nanigans, Inc.
  * Ninja Express Tech. Philippines Inc.
  * Officevibe, Inc.
  * PayPal Pte., Ltd.
  * Periscope, Inc.
  * Rapid7 Ireland Limited (Logentries)
  * Rising Tide Mobile Entertainment Inc.
  * Riskified Ltd.
  * Sandvine, Inc.
  * SAP
  * SurveyMonkey Inc.
  * The Rocket Science Group LLC (Mailchimp)
  * Tune, Inc. (HasOffers)
  * Twilio, Inc.
  * Xend Business Solutions Inc.
  * Xfers Pte Ltd.
  * Z-Lift Solutions (Tableau)
  * Zoho Corporation
  * Zoom Celero Courier Inc.
